You are the Empress Dowager of the Yong Kingdom,
أنت الإمبراطورة الأرملة لمملكة يونغ ،
with supreme power in your hands.
مع القوة المطلقة بين يديك.
Since you could sacrifice your own child
لأنك تستطيع أن تضحي بطفلك
for power and all,
من أجل السلطة والجميع ،
watch them crumble before your own eyes.
شاهدهم ينهارون أمام أعينكم.
Mother.
الأم.
Don't you love power most?
ألا تحب القوة أكثر؟
After all these people are dead,
بعد أن مات كل هؤلاء الناس ،
how about you
ماذا عنك
go underground
اذهب تحت الأرض
to be the supreme Empress Dowager?
لتكون الإمبراطورة الأرملة؟
Power is inherently ruthless.
القوة بطبيعتها لا ترحم.
Don't you want me to bow my head.
لا تريدني أن أحني رأسي.
Even at this moment,
حتى في هذه اللحظة ،
you still don't admit your mistakes
ما زلت لا تعترف بأخطائك
and regret it?
وتندم عليه؟
Mother.
الأم.
I just want to hear you say
أريد فقط أن أسمعك تقول
you regret it.
أنت تندم عليه.
Have you ever
هل سبق لك
cared about me?
اهتم بي؟
I never regret it.
أنا لا أندم على ذلك أبدا.
And I have to thank you.
ويجب أن أشكرك.
After tonight,
بعد هذه الليلة،
all the people in the whole city will be dead.
يموت كل الشعب في المدينة كلها.
Then no one will know my secret,
ثم لن يعرف أحد سرّي ،
and I will still have an everlasting name.
وسيظل لي اسم أبدي.
Okay.
تمام.
Since you are still so stubborn,
بما أنك لا تزال عنيدًا جدًا ،
die
موت
with your power.
بقوتك.
(The prince is recovering from a serious illness.)
(الأمير يتعافى من مرض خطير).
(It's a great thing.)
(إنه شيء عظيم.)
(Why do you have to throw away)
(لماذا عليك التخلص)
(all the epiphyllum in the palace?)
(كل epiphyllum في القصر؟)
(Throw them away.)
(ارمهم بعيدًا).
(Take this epiphyllum and go.)
(خذ هذا epiphyllum واذهب.)
(The name Tan'er)
(اسم تنير)
(only belongs to you.)
(ملك لك فقط.)
(But isn't this your favorite flower?)
(لكن أليست هذه هي الزهرة المفضلة لديك؟)
(Throw them away.)
(ارمهم بعيدًا).
Tan'er.
تان.
Your nickname
اسم الشهرة الخاص بك
is Tan'er.
هو تان.
=A League of Nobleman=
= عصبة النبلاء =
=Episode 29=
= الحلقة 29 =
It's for you.
إنه لك.
Thank you.
شكرًا لك.
Hold it tight.
امسك بقوة.
It's for you.
إنه لك.
Come on. It's for you.
تعال.  إنه لك.
Thank you.
شكرًا لك.
Take it.
خذها.
Here you are.
تفضل.
We have spent so much effort
لقد بذلنا الكثير من الجهد
just to stop it all,
فقط لوقف كل شيء ،
but we still cannot escape it.
لكننا ما زلنا لا نستطيع الهروب منه.
We'd better run.
من الأفضل أن نجري.
Save as many people as we can.
إنقاذ أكبر عدد ممكن من الناس.
Otherwise we all have to die here.
وإلا علينا جميعا أن نموت هنا.
I got it.
حصلت عليه.
Rain.
مطر.
As long as it rains,
ما دامت تمطر ،
the pollen doesn't get airborne.
حبوب اللقاح لا تنتشر في الهواء.
Good idea.
فكره جيده.
Before or after Grain Rain,
قبل أمطار الحبوب أو بعدها ،
when the clouds become like this, the rain will fall.
عندما تصبح الغيوم هكذا ، سوف يسقط المطر.
It looks like
يبدو
it's going to rain.
ستمطر.
But we don't know when.
لكننا لا نعرف متى.
Use a rain catcher.
استخدم صائد المطر.
Just sprinkle a lot of salt into the rain catcher,
فقط رش الكثير من الملح في صائد المطر
ignite it with gunpowder,
أشعلوه بالبارود ،
sprinkle the salt high into the sky,
يرش الملح عاليا في السماء ،
and it will turn clouds into rain.
وسيحول السحب إلى مطر.
Generally, the rain catcher is built on a high place.
بشكل عام ، صائد المطر مبني على مكان مرتفع.
And the rain catcher in the capital
وماسك المطر في العاصمة
is on Yunxiao Mountain.
يقع على جبل Yunxiao.
The Ministry of Rites
وزارة الطقوس
has documented the use of rain catcher.
وقد وثق استخدام ماسك المطر.
It's just that it hasn't been used for years,
كل ما في الأمر أنه لم يتم استخدامه منذ سنوات ،
and it's probably obsolete.
وربما عفا عليها الزمن.
Cannons can be used instead.
يمكن استخدام المدافع بدلاً من ذلك.
Okay.
تمام.
Let's split up.
دعونا تقسيم.
There are cannon and ammunition at the gate of the city.
هناك مدفع وذخيرة على بوابة المدينة.
I'm sending someone to fetch them now.
أنا أرسل شخصًا لجلبهم الآن.
I will escort the people.
سأرافق الناس.
I am familiar with the terrain of the capital,
أنا على دراية بتضاريس العاصمة ،
and I can assist Mr. Lan.
ويمكنني مساعدة السيد لان.
Then I'll get the salt.
ثم سأحضر الملح.
I need some helpers.
انا بحاجة الى بعض المساعدين.
I am willing to go.
أنا على استعداد للذهاب.
In front of the disaster,
أمام الكارثة ،
I am willing to make my humble effort.
أنا على استعداد لبذل جهدي المتواضع.
I am also going.
أنا أيضا ذاهب.
It's just that
إنه فقط كذلك
we need to move much salt up the mountain.
نحن بحاجة إلى نقل الكثير من الملح إلى أعلى الجبل.
I'm afraid that you...
أخشى أنك ...
We are going.
نحن ذاهبون.
Sir.
سيد.
Xu Dong.
شو دونغ.
You...
أنت...
This is the first time we have disobeyed your will.
هذه هي المرة الأولى التي عصينا فيها إرادتك.
But we are willing to
لكننا على استعداد لذلك
live and die with you.
عش وتموت معك.
Yes.
نعم.
We will be wherever you are.
سنكون أينما كنت.
Okay.
تمام.
Sirs,
السادة ،
please help me
الرجاء مساعدتي
evacuate the people
إجلاء الناس
and escort them up the mountain.
واصطحبهم إلى أعلى الجبل.
The terrain there is high,
التضاريس هناك مرتفعة ،
and it may be safer.
وقد يكون أكثر أمانًا.
Go.
يذهب.
Let's split up and save people.
دعونا نقسم الناس وننقذهم.
Let's go find salt.
دعنا نذهب للبحث عن الملح.
Come on.
تعال.
This way.
من هنا.
Here.
هنا.
This...
هذا...
That's far from enough.
هذا بعيد عن أن يكون كافيا.
Yes.
نعم.
Look for more.
ابحث عن المزيد.
Not these ones.
ليس هؤلاء.
Let's go to another place.
دعنا نذهب إلى مكان آخر.
I am a salt merchant.
أنا تاجر ملح.
What do you need salt for?
لماذا تحتاج الملح؟
We will bring rain with salt.
سنجلب المطر بالملح.
As long as it rains,
ما دامت تمطر ،
the capital will be saved.
سيتم حفظ العاصمة.
The salt from my shop
الملح من متجري
has just arrived at the wharf,
وصل للتو إلى رصيف الميناء ،
and it weighs 600 catties.
ويزن 600 كاتي.
I am willing to contribute the entire inventory.
أنا على استعداد للمساهمة في المخزون بأكمله.
I can take you there.
أستطيع أخذك هناك.
Thanks so much.
ًشكراً جزيلا.
Here.
هنا.
Come on.
تعال.
Zhang Ping.
تشانغ بينغ.
We have enough people.
لدينا عدد كاف من الناس.
Go help Mr. Lan.
اذهب لمساعدة السيد لان.
Yes.
نعم.
Okay.
تمام.
Take care.
يعتني.
Don't worry.
لا تقلق.
Let's go.
دعنا نذهب.
Go.
يذهب.
Everyone.
الجميع.
Put on a face towel to cover your mouth and nose.
ضع منشفة وجه لتغطية فمك وأنفك.
Hurry up to Yunxiao Mountain, don't stay in a low place.
سارعوا إلى جبل يونشياو ، ولا تبقىوا في مكان منخفض.
Hurry up to Yunxiao Mountain. Put on a face towel
اسرع حتى جبل Yunxiao.  ضع منشفة وجه
to cover your mouth and nose.
لتغطية فمك وأنفك.
Grandpa.
الجد.
Grandpa Yang.
الجد يانغ.
The capital is so large.
العاصمة كبيرة جدا.
But I am all alone.
لكني أنا وحيد.
What about those who cannot hear?
ماذا عن أولئك الذين لا يسمعون؟
Everyone.
الجميع.
Don't be afraid of the poisonous mist.
لا تخافوا من الضباب السام.
Don't linger in the low places.
لا تتباطأ في الأماكن المنخفضة.
Go to Yunxiao Mountain as soon as possible.
اذهب إلى جبل Yunxiao في أسرع وقت ممكن.
Xu Lu, Wang Cheng, why are you here?
شو لو وانغ تشنغ لماذا أنت هنا؟
You can't be a hero alone.
لا يمكنك أن تكون بطلاً بمفردك.
If we see the people suffer and stay out of it,
إذا رأينا الناس يعانون وبقيوا خارجها ،
our study will be in vain.
دراستنا سوف تذهب سدى.
- Exactly.
- بالضبط.  - بالضبط.
Everyone.
الجميع.
Put on a face towel to cover your mouth and nose.
ضع منشفة وجه لتغطية فمك وأنفك.
You should go there.
يجب أن تذهب هناك.
Cover your mouth and nose.
غطي فمك وأنفك.
Put on a face towel to cover your mouth and nose.
ضع منشفة وجه لتغطية فمك وأنفك.
Everyone, hurry up.
الجميع ، أسرعوا.
We are almost there.
نحن على وشك الانتهاء.
Go.
يذهب.
My revenge succeeded.
نجح ثأري.
My revenge succeeded...
نجح ثأري ...
The scarlet mist...
الضباب القرمزي ...
The scarlet mist is coming again.
الضباب القرمزي يأتي مرة أخرى.
Run!
يجري!
The scarlet mist is coming.
الضباب القرمزي قادم.
Bros, come on.
إخوان ، تعال.
Hurry up.
أسرع - بسرعة.
Take care.
يعتني.
Come on.
تعال.
Put it here.
ضعه هنا.
- Here. - Be gentle.
- هنا.  - كن لطيفآ.
Hurry up.
أسرع - بسرعة.
Come on.
تعال.
Mix them well.
اخلطيهم جيدا.
Be careful.
احرص.
Mix the salt and gunpowder.
اخلطي الملح والبارود.
Load them into shells.
تحميلهم في قذائف.
Hurry up.
أسرع - بسرعة.
Come on.
تعال.
Pour it.
صبها.
Hold tight.
تمسك جيدا.
Reload
إعادة تحميل
and induce rain.
والحث على المطر.
Reload.
إعادة تحميل.
Baby.
طفل.
My baby.
طفلي.
Thank you.
شكرًا لك.
Reload. Once more.
إعادة تحميل.  مرة أخرى.
General.
عام.
The salt bomb has run out.
نفدت قنبلة الملح.
Then
ثم
it's up to God's will.
الأمر متروك لمشيئة الله.
What to do?
ما يجب القيام به؟
Why hasn't Mr. Lan arrived?
لماذا لم يصل السيد لان؟
Mr. Xu.
السيد شو.
Where is Mr. Lan?
أين السيد لان؟
He insisted on leaving
أصر على المغادرة
after everyone went up the mountain.
بعد أن صعد الجميع الجبل.
He is probably behind.
ربما يكون في الخلف.
Where is Zhang?
أين تشانغ؟
He's with Mr. Lan.
إنه مع السيد لان.
Zhang.
تشانغ.
Why don't you come up?
لماذا لا تأتي؟
Mr. Lan is back.
السيد لان عاد.
Zhang.
تشانغ.
Take care.
يعتني.
Sir.
سيد.
How is it?
كيف هذا؟
I'm glad you are fine.
أنا سعيد أنك بخير.
Are you okay?
هل أنت بخير؟
Yes.
نعم.
Zhang Ping.
تشانغ بينغ.
If I'm going to die today,
إذا كنت سأموت اليوم ،
I don't want to have
لا أريد أن أمتلك
anything to do with you in the next life.
أي شيء يتعلق بك في الحياة القادمة.
I don't believe in ghosts and gods,
أنا لا أؤمن بالأشباح والآلهة ،
nor do I believe in an afterlife.
ولا أؤمن بآخرة.
You are still a spoiler.
أنت لا تزال مفسد.
It's raining.
انها تمطر.
Yes.
نعم.
Great.
عظيم.
Finally.
أخيراً.
Mr. Lan.
السيد.  لان.
This orchid sachet
هذا الكيس الأوركيد
was given to me
أعطيت لي
by your father 20 years ago.
بواسطة والدك قبل 20 عاما.
Now
الآن
I'm returning it to its original owner.
سأعيدها إلى مالكها الأصلي.
Hurry up.
أسرع - بسرعة.
Let me.
دعني.
One for me.
واحده لي.
Okay.
تمام.
Take care.
يعتني.
Granny.
الجدة.
Grandpa Yang is gone.
رحل الجد يانغ.
But you still have me and Zhang Ping.
لكن لا يزال لديك أنا وزانغ بينغ.
Don't worry.
لا تقلق.
From now on, Zhang and I
من الآن فصاعدًا ، أنا وزانغ
will come to help you every week.
سيأتي لمساعدتك كل أسبوع.
It's my fault.
هذا خطأي.
Mr. Wang.
السيد وانج.
Look at you...
انظر لحالك...
News of victory!
أخبار النصر!
His Majesty
جلالته
came back in triumph.
عاد منتصرا.
- Victory! - It's victory!
- فوز!  - إنه انتصار!
I heard that the capital was in great trouble,
سمعت أن العاصمة كانت في ورطة كبيرة ،
so I led an elite trooper to support.
لذلك قادت جنديًا من النخبة لتقديم الدعم.
Mr. Liu.
السيد.  ليو.
Are you fine?
هل أنت بخير؟
Your Majesty.
جلالة الملك.
I...
أنا...
Welcome Your Majesty to come back in triumph.
نرحب بجلالة الملك للعودة منتصرا.
Arise.
تنشأ.
Thank you, Your Majesty.
شكرا لك جلالة الملك.
My son.
ابني.
Great.
عظيم.
Ziyi.
هم انهم.
Dad.
أب.
My son.
ابني.
(Hanhui Pavilion, Ning'an)
(جناح هانهوي ، نينغان)
For the past 20 years,
على مدار العشرين عامًا الماضية ،
the Empress Dowager ruled the government,
حكمت الإمبراطورة الأرملة الحكومة ،
and the common people were full of grievances.
وكان عامة الناس مليئين بالمظالم.
I have always worried about
لطالما كنت قلقة بشأنه
whether I can be a good emperor.
هل يمكنني أن أكون إمبراطورًا جيدًا.
But now
لكن الآن
I don't worry about it anymore.
لا تقلق بشأن ذلك بعد الآن.
I am going to create a new look
انا ذاهب لخلق مظهر جديد
and return the beloved motherland to the people.
وإعادة الوطن الحبيب للشعب.
Don't you care whether my bloodline is true or not?
ألا تهتم بما إذا كانت سلالتي صحيحة أم لا؟
I only know that
أنا أعرف ذلك فقط
the one who can make the people live and work in peace and contentment,
الشخص الذي يمكن أن يجعل الناس يعيشون ويعملون بسلام ورضا ،
and free the world of crimes
وتحرير العالم من الجرائم
is a good emperor.
هو إمبراطور جيد.
Do you know
هل تعرف
why I sent you to be the magistrate of Yiping County?
لماذا أرسلتك لتكون قاضي الصلح في مقاطعة ييبينغ؟
Why?
لماذا؟
Right now, the aftermath of the capital is not over yet.
في الوقت الحالي ، لم تنتهِ آثار العاصمة بعد.
The Empress Dowager's remnant party hasn't been totally eliminated.
لم يتم القضاء تمامًا على الطرف المتبقي من The Empress Dowager.
You are upright.
انت مستقيم.
If you are involved in it,
إذا كنت منخرطًا في ذلك ،
it will be very dangerous.
سيكون خطيرا جدا.
You'd better be trained outside
من الأفضل أن تتدرب في الخارج
for a few years first.
لبضع سنوات أولا.
A few years?
سنوات قليلة؟
I expect a lot from you.
اتوقع منك الكثير.
In the future,
فى المستقبل،
you will be the Minister of the Court of Judicial Review.
ستكون وزير محكمة المراجعة القضائية.
Of course.
بالطبع.
You will even be prime minister.
سوف تكون حتى رئيس الوزراء.
But I...
لكن أنا...
You still want to go to the Court of Judicial Review.
ما زلت تريد الذهاب إلى محكمة المراجعة القضائية.
I know.
أنا أعرف.
Yes,
نعم،
Your Majesty.
جلالة الملك.
♪Go to take office♪
♪ اذهب لتولي المنصب
♪in Yiping County♪
♪ في مقاطعة ييبينغ ♪
♪You are the county magistrate, I will manage the accounts♪
أنت قاضي المقاطعة ، وسأدير الحسابات
♪You cook noodles♪
أنت تطبخ المعكرونة ♪
♪I will add firewood♪
♪ سأضيف الحطب ♪
Zhang.
تشانغ.
You are about to become the county magistrate,
أنت على وشك أن تصبح قاضي المقاطعة ،
why are you still frowning?
لماذا مازلت عابس
This is an opportunity
هذه فرصة
that countless scholars dream of.
الذي يحلم به عدد لا يحصى من العلماء.
Don't worry.
لا تقلق.
After arriving in Yiping County,
بعد وصوله إلى مقاطعة ييبينغ ،
I will definitely help you
سأساعدك بالتأكيد
manage the accounts clearly.
إدارة الحسابات بشكل واضح.
I was thinking that I could only investigate cases.
كنت أفكر في أنه يمكنني فقط التحقيق في القضايا.
As for being the county magistrate...
أما عن كونه قاضي المقاطعة ...
His Majesty said that
قال جلالة الملك ذلك
you can even be prime minister.
يمكنك حتى أن تكون رئيسًا للوزراء.
A mere county magistrate would be easy for you.
إن مجرد قاضي الصلح سيكون أمرًا سهلاً بالنسبة لك.
Our life will definitely get better and better.
ستتحسن حياتنا بالتأكيد وأفضل.
Everything will be better
كل شيء سيكون أفضل
when you become prime minister.
عندما تصبح رئيسا للوزراء.
(Court of Judicial Review)
(محكمة المراجعة القضائية)
My mother is so good at cooking.
والدتي بارعة في الطبخ.
Yes.
نعم.
It's your turn.
إنه دورك.
I wonder
انا اتعجب
who is
الذي هو
the new Minister of the Court of Judicial Review.
الوزير الجديد لمحكمة المراجعة القضائية.
Just enjoy ourselves
فقط استمتع بأنفسنا
as usual
كل عادة
no matter who comes.
بغض النظر عمن يأتي.
Yes.
نعم.
Mr. Wang.
السيد وانج.
Could it be that you are
هل يمكن أن تكون أنت
the new Minister of the Court of Judicial Review?
الوزير الجديد لمحكمة المراجعة القضائية؟
Could it be you?
يمكن أن يكون لك؟
Someone.
شخص ما.
Yes.
نعم.
Move out all the files backlogged
نقل جميع الملفات المتراكمة
in the case archive.
في أرشيف الحالة.
Yes.
نعم.
Sir.
سيد.
Now your father was cleared of wrongdoing.
الآن تم تبرئة والدك من الخطأ.
You can finally relax.
يمكنك أخيرا الاسترخاء.
You can also take the young master
يمكنك أيضًا أن تأخذ السيد الشاب
back to the mansion for reunion.
العودة إلى القصر من أجل لم الشمل.
Over the years, I had been in deep crisis
على مر السنين ، كنت في أزمة عميقة
to clear my father's grievances.
لتوضيح مظالم والدي.
I was afraid of hurting Lan Hui,
كنت خائفة من إيذاء لان هوي ،
so I fostered him in the countryside,
لذلك رعته في الريف ،
which made him suffer a lot.
مما جعله يعاني كثيرا.
The young master said that
قال السيد الشاب ذلك
he has grown up
لقد كبر
and will clean up the world with you from now on.
وسوف ينظف العالم معك من الآن فصاعدًا.
(It's a pity that Congrou left too early)
(من المؤسف أن كونجرو غادر مبكرًا جدًا)
(to see this day.)
(لنرى هذا اليوم.)
Madam will surely bless you
ستباركك سيدتي بالتأكيد
and the young master in heaven.
والسيد الشاب في الجنة.
(Yiping County)
(مقاطعة ييبينغ)
Zhang.
تشانغ.
I don't understand.
لا أفهم.
You are now the county magistrate.
أنت الآن قاضي المقاطعة.
Why are you still selling noodles?
لماذا ما زلت تبيع المعكرونة؟
It's my hobby.
انها هوايتي.
Sir.
سيد.
Are my noodles ready?
هل المعكرونة الخاصة بي جاهزة؟
Coming.
آت.
Your noodles.
المعكرونة الخاصة بك.
- Please enjoy. - Thanks.
- من فضلك استمتع.  - شكرًا.
Mr. Lan.
السيد.  لان.
Why are you here?
لماذا أنت هنا؟
Let's go.
دعنا نذهب.
Xu Dong.
شو دونغ.
Zhang Ping.
تشانغ بينغ.
Mr. Zhang.
السيد تشانغ.
Xu Dong, why are you here?
شو دونغ ، لماذا أنت هنا؟
Mr. Lan is now transferred to be the governor,
تم نقل السيد لان الآن ليكون الحاكم ،
to patrol the counties on behalf of the Emperor.
لتسيير دوريات في المقاطعات نيابة عن الإمبراطور.
Wherever he went,
أينما ذهب ،
he proclaimed the imperial edict,
أعلن المرسوم الإمبراطوري ،
praised virtue and punished vice,
امتدح الفضيلة وعاقب الرذيلة ،
understood the sufferings of people's livelihood,
يفهم معاناة الناس في رزقهم ،
and solved outstanding cases.
وحل القضايا المعلقة.
Is this your first time in Yiping County?
هل هذه هي المرة الأولى لك في مقاطعة ييبينغ؟
I will show you around.
وسوف تظهر لك حول.
- Let's go.
- دعنا نذهب.  - دعنا نذهب.
Sir.
سيد.
Look.
ينظر.
So lively.
حيوية جدا.
I was passing through Yiping County,
كنت أعبر مقاطعة ييبينغ ،
and I thought you were here,
واعتقدت أنك هنا ،
so I came to pay a visit.
لذلك جئت للقيام بزيارة.
I have five pennies.
لدي خمسة بنسات.
May I buy noodles from you?
هل يمكنني شراء المعكرونة منك؟
♪The white horse in the early morning market♪
♪ الحصان الأبيض في سوق الصباح الباكر ♪
♪Light up the stove, smoke curling up♪
♪ أشعل الموقد والدخان يتجعد ♪
♪Hasty pedestrians put down their luggage♪
يسارع المشاة في وضع أمتعتهم
♪How much is the noodle with an egg♪
كم ثمن المعكرونة مع بيضة
(Hey, a bowl of noodles with a poached egg.)
(مرحبًا ، وعاء من المعكرونة مع بيض مسلوق.)
(Got it.)
(فهمتها.)
♪A kid is lingering around the ice-cream stall♪
♪ طفل عالق حول كشك الآيس كريم
♪Drooling with crying eyes♪
♪ سيلان اللعاب بأعين باكية
♪More raisins and candied fruit♪
المزيد من الزبيب والفواكه المسكرة ♪
♪Raising mouth, sweet smile♪
♪ رفع الفم ابتسامة حلوة ♪
♪Granny is chasing grandpa♪
♪ الجدة تطارد الجد
♪The male guests in the bathhouse fled away♪
هرب الضيوف الذكور في الحمام بعيدًا
♪Zhang overturned the chessboard again♪
♪ قلب تشانغ رقعة الشطرنج مرة أخرى ♪
♪This round doesn't count, one more round♪
♪ هذه الجولة لا تحسب ، جولة أخرى ♪
♪Sweet watermelon, cold ice-cream, refreshing in the bath, cool cattail fan♪
♪ بطيخ حلو ، آيس كريم بارد ، منعش في الحمام ، مروحة كاتايل باردة ♪
♪The sun sets on the horizon♪
غروب الشمس في الأفق
♪The evening lights are lit♪
♪ أنوار المساء مضاءة
♪The market is getting quiet and the alley is with snore♪
السوق يهدأ والزقاق فيه شخير
♪Make another bonfire♪
♪ أشعل نارًا أخرى ♪
♪Guard the peace of the night♪
حافظ على هدوء الليل ♪
♪Pepper hemp, glutinous rice cakes, strong old wine, fragrant pancakes♪
♪ قنب الفلفل ، كعك الأرز الدبق ، نبيذ قديم قوي ، فطائر معطرة ♪
♪Let's watch the rainbow together♪
♪ لنشاهد قوس قزح معًا
♪Let's climb the mountain together♪
♪ لنسلق الجبل معًا
♪Talking about the big world and small dreams♪
♪ نتحدث عن العالم الكبير والأحلام الصغيرة
♪May tomorrow morning♪
♪ قد صباح الغد ♪
♪Still look like today♪
♪ لا تزال تبدو مثل اليوم ♪
♪The white horse in the early morning market♪
♪ الحصان الأبيض في سوق الصباح الباكر ♪
♪Light up the stove, smoke curling up♪
♪ أشعل الموقد والدخان يتجعد ♪
♪Hasty pedestrians put down their luggage♪
يسارع المشاة في وضع أمتعتهم
♪How much is the noodle with an egg♪
كم ثمن المعكرونة مع بيضة
♪Ziyi who garrisons the frontiers sent another letter home♪
♪ أرسل زيي الذي يحمي الحدود رسالة أخرى إلى الوطن ♪
♪Uncle Yu from the bun shop lost a pork leg bone♪
♪ فقد العم يو من متجر الكعك عظمة ساق لحم الخنزير ♪
♪The letter made the family want to cry♪
الرسالة جعلت الأسرة تريد البكاء ♪
♪The burglar is a stray yellow dog♪
السارق كلب أصفر ضال ♪
♪Sweet watermelon, cold ice-cream, refreshing in the bath, cool cattail fan♪
♪ بطيخ حلو ، آيس كريم بارد ، منعش في الحمام ، مروحة كاتايل باردة ♪
♪The sun sets on the horizon♪
غروب الشمس في الأفق
♪The evening lights are lit♪
♪ أنوار المساء مضاءة
♪The market is getting quiet and the alley is with snore♪
السوق يهدأ والزقاق فيه شخير
♪Make another bonfire♪
♪ أشعل نارًا أخرى ♪
♪Guard the peace of the night♪
حافظ على هدوء الليل ♪
♪Pepper hemp, glutinous rice cakes, strong old wine, fragrant pancakes♪
♪ قنب الفلفل ، كعك الأرز الدبق ، نبيذ قديم قوي ، فطائر معطرة ♪
♪Let's watch the rainbow together♪
♪ لنشاهد قوس قزح معًا
♪Let's climb the mountain together♪
♪ لنسلق الجبل معًا
♪Talking about the big world and small dreams♪
♪ نتحدث عن العالم الكبير والأحلام الصغيرة
♪May tomorrow morning♪
♪ قد صباح الغد ♪
♪Still look like today♪
♪ لا تزال تبدو مثل اليوم ♪